<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AI by Mai</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on AI by Mai</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is complexity in machine learning systems justified?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/complexity_and_congnitive_load/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/complexity_and_congnitive_load/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machine learning systems are becoming increasingly sophisticated, and a critical question emerges: Is the growing complexity of these systems truly justified, or are we building solutions that exceed our cognitive capacity to understand and maintain them?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The concept of &lt;a href=&#34;https://thevaluable.dev/cognitive-load-theory-software-developer/&#34;&gt;cognitive load&lt;/a&gt;, introduced by John Sweller in 1988, suggests that our working memory can only handle a limited amount of information simultaneously. In machine learning and software development, this cognitive load refers to the mental effort required to understand, maintain, and operate systems. As systems grow in complexity, this load increases, potentially leading to reduced efficiency, higher error rates, and increased development time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;-about-me&#34;&gt;👩‍💻 About Me&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hi there! I&amp;rsquo;m Mai. I&amp;rsquo;m a Staff Software Engineer, with a passion for exploring the fascinating and ever-evolving world of Artificial Intelligence (AI). My journey in AI has been fueled by a deep curiosity about how technology can empower individuals and businesses to solve real-world problems. This blog, &amp;ldquo;AI by Mai,&amp;rdquo; is my corner of the internet where I unpack the &amp;ldquo;mysteries&amp;rdquo; of AI in a casual, approachable way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-my-phd-research-section&#34;&gt;Welcome to My PhD Research Section&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Greetings! This is my PhD journey in Applied Artificial Intelligence, with a keen focus on the critical sub-field of fake news detection. My interest in this area was sparked during my master&amp;rsquo;s studies when I delved into the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.es/Social-Physics-Spread-Lessons-Science/dp/1594205655&#34;&gt;Social Physics&lt;/a&gt;. It was at that moment when I realized that fake news detection would become my primary research focus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given the format of my master&amp;rsquo;s thesis – structured by publications – I am excited to share all my research findings and advancements in this space through this platform.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
