<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AI by Mai</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on AI by Mai</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is complexity in machine learning systems justified?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/complexity_and_congnitive_load/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/complexity_and_congnitive_load/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machine learning systems are becoming increasingly sophisticated, and a critical question emerges: Is the growing complexity of these systems truly justified, or are we building solutions that exceed our cognitive capacity to understand and maintain them?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The concept of &lt;a href=&#34;https://thevaluable.dev/cognitive-load-theory-software-developer/&#34;&gt;cognitive load&lt;/a&gt;, introduced by John Sweller in 1988, suggests that our working memory can only handle a limited amount of information simultaneously. In machine learning and software development, this cognitive load refers to the mental effort required to understand, maintain, and operate systems. As systems grow in complexity, this load increases, potentially leading to reduced efficiency, higher error rates, and increased development time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;-about-me&#34;&gt;👩‍💻 About Me&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Mai, a Staff Software Engineer passionate about AI. At &amp;ldquo;AI by Mai,&amp;rdquo; I break down complex AI concepts in a casual, approachable way. I&amp;rsquo;ve led teams developing machine learning models for cybersecurity, industrial predictive control systems, and marketplace optimization. My work spans from LLMs to real-time system optimization, focusing on practical applications that create real impact.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;-what-i-write-about&#34;&gt;💡 What I Write About&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AI concepts and trends in plain language&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
